// import shuffleArray from "../helpers/shuffleArray.js";

// import { getRandomItem } from "../helpers/shuffleAnswer.js";
// const getRandomItem = (array) =>
//   array[Math.floor(Math.random() * array.length)];

export const JamesBondQuestions = [
  {
    question:
      "Which celebration in Mexico features in the opening scene of Spectre?",
    options: ["Mardi Gras", "Day of the Dead", "Christmas", "Funeral"],
    correctAnswer: "Day of the Dead",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is featured to the right of the 007 numbers of the 007 logo?",
    options: ["Gun", "Heart", "England's Flag", "Silloette"],
    correctAnswer: "Gun",
  },
  {
    question: "What is a Walther PPK?",
    options: ["Handbook", "Rifle", "Automobile", "Gun"],
    correctAnswer: "Gun",
  },
  {
    question:
      "How many different actors played James Bond in the film series during the '90s?",
    options: ["1", "5", "3", "6"],
    correctAnswer: "1",
  },
  {
    question: "In a word, what is James Bond's profession?",
    options: ["Assassin", "Secret Agent", "Spy", "Killer"],
    correctAnswer: "Spy",
  },
  {
    question: "Which government department does James Bond work for?",
    options: ["MI6", "Assassin", "MI5", "Search & Rescue"],
    correctAnswer: "MI6",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The release of the film No Time To Die was delayed due to COVID-19. When was it supposed to open?",
    options: ["July 4", "May 30", "September 11", "April 20"],
    correctAnswer: "April 20",
  },
  {
    question: "How many Bond films have starred Timothy Dalton?",
    options: ["Zero", "One", "Two", "Three"],
    correctAnswer: "Two",
  },
  {
    question: "What do Bond and Le Chiffre play in Casino Royale?",
    options: ["Gin", "Poker", "Gamblers", "Cards"],
    correctAnswer: "Cards",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In which year in the 60s did the first James Bond film get released?",
    options: ["1962", "1960", "1964", "1968"],
    correctAnswer: "1962",
  },
  {
    question: "How many James Bond films did the character Jaws appear in?",
    options: ["1", "Two", "3", "Four"],
    correctAnswer: "Two",
  },
  {
    question: "What was Pierce Brosnan's first film as James Bond?",
    options: ["Casino Royale", "Moonraker", "Live and Let Die", "Goldeneye"],
    correctAnswer: "Goldeneye",
  },
  {
    question: "What is James Bond's identity number?",
    options: ["6", "7", "8", "1"],
    correctAnswer: "7",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the smallest planet in our solar system?",
    options: ["Earth", "Mars", "Mercury", "Venus"],
    correctAnswer: "Mercury",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which James Bond Villain had a midget sidekick called Nick-Knack?",
    options: ["Scaramanga", "Dr No", "Jaws", "Big E"],
    correctAnswer: "Scaramanga",
  },
  {
    question: "Who did Joseph Wiseman play in a Bond film?",
    options: ["Bill", "Mr Right", "Spectre", "Dr No"],
    correctAnswer: "Dr No",
  },
  {
    question: "In which Bond film does Oddjob appear?",
    options: ["Live and Let Die", "Goldfinger", "Moonraker", "Dr No"],
    correctAnswer: "Goldfinger",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which James Bond film title is also the name of a breed of duck?",
    options: ["Alabio", "Mallard", "Goldeneye", "Daffy"],
    correctAnswer: "Goldeneye",
  },
  {
    question: "In Casino Royale the game played by James Bond is?",
    options: ["Go Fish", "Blackjack", "Poker", "Spades"],
    correctAnswer: "Poker",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In which film does James Bond tangle with the turbanned Gobinda?",
    options: [
      "Octopussy",
      "The Man with the Golden Gun",
      "Thunderball",
      "Goldfinger",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Octopussy",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of these has not played James Bond?",
    options: [
      "Roger Moore",
      "Richard Burton",
      "Timothy Dalton",
      "Sean Connery",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Richard Burton",
  },
  {
    question:
      "James Bond was searching for what kind of airplane in Thunderball?",
    options: ["Bird of Prey", "747", "Mercury", "Vulcan"],
    correctAnswer: "Vulcan",
  },
  {
    question: "Who was the villain in the Bond movie, Diamonds Are Forever?",
    options: ["Shaw", "Dr Evil", "Blofeld", "Iron Claw"],
    correctAnswer: "Blofeld",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In which James Bond film does Jaws bite through a cable car cable?",
    options: [
      "Thunderball",
      "You Only Live Twice",
      "Moonraker",
      "From Russia with Love",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Moonraker",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which James Bond movie features 007 playing his arch-enemy in a round of golf at Royal St. Georges, Sandwich?",
    options: [
      "Goldfinger",
      "The Spy Who Loved Me",
      "On Her Majestys Secret Service",
      "License To Kill",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Goldfinger",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What eye-bleeding villain tortures James Bond with a knotted rope in 2006's Casino Royale?",
    options: ["Macbeth", "Felix", "The Beast", "Dr No"],
    correctAnswer: "Le Chiffre",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who is responsible for providing all of James Bond's equipment and gadgets?",
    options: ["B", "Q", "M", "R"],
    correctAnswer: "Q",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of these is a long-running Bond character?",
    options: ["Mr Big", "Miss Moneypenny", "Winston", "Walter"],
    correctAnswer: "Miss Moneypenny",
  },
  {
    question: "Who directed the James Bond film 'Skyfall'?",
    options: [
      "Mickey Mantle",
      "Lorne Michaels",
      "Sam Mendes",
      "Quentin Tarantino",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Sam Mendes",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What kind of car does James Bond win in a poker game in 2006's 'Casino Royale'?",
    options: ["Aston Martin", "BMW", "Alfa Romeo", "Ferrari"],
    correctAnswer: "Aston Martin",
  },
  {
    question: "Who played James Bond in 'Diamonds Are Forever'?",
    options: ["Roger Moore", "Sean Connery", "Timothy Dalton", "Errol Flynn"],
    correctAnswer: "Sean Connery",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which Bond actor portrayed the character, James Bond, during most of the 1960s?",
    options: [
      "Sidney Poitier",
      "Roger Moore",
      "Pierce Brosnan",
      "Sean Connery",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Sean Connery",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the highest grossing James Bond movie of all time if you take inflation into account?",
    options: ["Skyfall", "Casino Royale", "A View To A Kill", "Thunderball"],
    correctAnswer: "Thunderball",
  },
  {
    question: "Tom Jones sang for which Bond film?",
    options: ["Moonraker", "You Only Live Twice", "Thunderball", "Dr No"],
    correctAnswer: "Thunderball",
  },
  {
    question: "What was Daniel Craig's first James Bond film?",
    options: ["Goldeneye", "Casino Royale", "Quantum of Solace", "Skyfall"],
    correctAnswer: "Casino Royale",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who sang the title track to the James Bond movie, 'License To Kill'",
    options: ["Gladys Knight", "Huey Lewis", "Madonna", "Eartha Kitt"],
    correctAnswer: "Gladys Knight",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Complete the name of this James Bond film. 'From Russia With___'",
    options: ["Me", "Love", "Guns", "Us"],
    correctAnswer: "Love",
  },
  {
    question: "Complete the name of this James Bond film. 'Die Another ___'",
    options: ["Time", "Way", "Day", "Century"],
    correctAnswer: "Day",
  },
  {
    question: "Complete the title of the 2002 Bond film: 'Die Another ...'",
    options: ["Way", "Tomorrow", "Day", "Time"],
    correctAnswer: "Day",
  },
  {
    question: "Complete the name of this James Bond film. 'Dr.___'",
    options: ["Evil", "Nefarious", "Smith", "No"],
    correctAnswer: "No",
  },
  {
    question: "Complete the name of this James Bond film. 'You Only Live ___'",
    options: ["Today", "Now", "Once", "Twice"],
    correctAnswer: "Twice",
  },
  {
    question: "Complete the name of this James Bond film. 'Live and Let ___'",
    options: ["Fly", "Run", "Die", "Live"],
    correctAnswer: "Die",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Complete the name of this James Bond film. 'The Spy Who Loved ___'",
    options: ["You", "Me", "Us", "Planes"],
    correctAnswer: "Me",
  },
  {
    question: "Complete the name of this James Bond film. 'A View to a ___'",
    options: ["Kill", "Window", "Shot", "Ace"],
    correctAnswer: "Kill",
  },
  {
    question: "Complete the name of this James Bond film. 'License to ___'",
    options: ["Spy", "Kill", "Shoot", "Run"],
    correctAnswer: "Kill",
  },
  {
    question: "Complete the name of this James Bond film. 'Diamonds Are ___'",
    options: ["Precious", "Mine", "Forever", "Beautiful"],
    correctAnswer: "Forever",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Complete the name of this James Bond film. 'On Her Majesty's Secret___'",
    options: ["Assassin", "Flag", "Service", "Board"],
    correctAnswer: "Service",
  },
  {
    question: "Complete the name of this James Bond film. 'Casino ___'",
    options: ["Market", "Flamingo", "Roulette", "Royale"],
    correctAnswer: "Royale",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Complete the name of this James Bond film. 'The World Is Not ___'",
    options: ["Wrong", "Mine", "Rough", "Enough"],
    correctAnswer: "Enough",
  },
  {
    question: "Complete the name of this James Bond film. 'The Living ___",
    options: ["Knockout", "Color", "Daylights", "Nightmare"],
    correctAnswer: "Daylights",
  },
  {
    question: "Complete the name of this James Bond film. 'Quantum of ___",
    options: ["Cheer", "Solace", "Support", "Relief"],
    correctAnswer: "Solace",
  },
  {
    question: "Complete the name of this James Bond film. 'Tomorrow Never ___'",
    options: ["Dies", "Lives", "Arrives", "Begins"],
    correctAnswer: "Dies",
  },
  {
    question: "Complete the name of this James Bond film. 'For Your Eyes ___'",
    options: ["Only", "Now", "Here", "Together"],
    correctAnswer: "Only",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Complete the name of this James Bond film. 'The Man with the Golden ___'",
    options: ["Pipe", "Gun", "Candlestick", "Wrench"],
    correctAnswer: "Gun",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which celebration in Mexico features in the opening scene of Spectre?",
    options: ["Mardi Gras", "Day of the Dead", "Christmas", "Funeral"],
    correctAnswer: "Day of the Dead",
  },
  {
    question: "Who was the first actor to play James Bond on screen?",
    options: ["Roger Moore", "Sean Connery", "David Niven", "Timothy Dalton"],
    correctAnswer: "Sean Connery",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the title of the first James Bond film?",
    options: ["Goldfinger", "Dr. No", "From Russia with Love", "Thunderball"],
    correctAnswer: "Dr. No",
  },
  {
    question: "Which Bond movie features a villain named Jaws?",
    options: [
      "Live and Let Die",
      "The Spy Who Loved Me",
      "Moonraker",
      "For Your Eyes Only",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "The Spy Who Loved Me",
  },
  {
    question: "Who sang the theme song for Skyfall?",
    options: ["Adele", "Madonna", "Sam Smith", "Shirley Bassey"],
    correctAnswer: "Adele",
  },
  {
    question: "What is James Bond’s codename?",
    options: ["001", "007", "009", "008"],
    correctAnswer: "007",
  },
  {
    question: "Which actress played Vesper Lynd in Casino Royale (2006)?",
    options: ["Eva Green", "Monica Bellucci", "Halle Berry", "Ursula Andress"],
    correctAnswer: "Eva Green",
  },
  {
    question: "Who directed the James Bond film GoldenEye?",
    options: ["Martin Campbell", "Sam Mendes", "Guy Hamilton", "John Glen"],
    correctAnswer: "Martin Campbell",
  },
  {
    question: "Which car brand is most associated with James Bond?",
    options: ["BMW", "Aston Martin", "Mercedes", "Jaguar"],
    correctAnswer: "Aston Martin",
  },
  {
    question: "In which Bond movie does the character 'Q' first appear?",
    options: ["Dr. No", "Goldfinger", "From Russia with Love", "Thunderball"],
    correctAnswer: "From Russia with Love",
  },
  {
    question: "Which James Bond movie features the song 'Live and Let Die'?",
    options: [
      "Live and Let Die",
      "Goldfinger",
      "The Spy Who Loved Me",
      "Moonraker",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Live and Let Die",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the villain in Goldfinger?",
    options: ["Scaramanga", "Dr. No", "Blofeld", "Auric Goldfinger"],
    correctAnswer: "Auric Goldfinger",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which actor played James Bond in On Her Majesty's Secret Service?",
    options: [
      "Sean Connery",
      "Roger Moore",
      "George Lazenby",
      "Timothy Dalton",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "George Lazenby",
  },
  {
    question: "In which Bond film does James Bond go to space?",
    options: [
      "Moonraker",
      "Diamonds Are Forever",
      "The Spy Who Loved Me",
      "Thunderball",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Moonraker",
  },
  {
    question: "Which actor played Bond's nemesis Blofeld in Spectre?",
    options: [
      "Christoph Waltz",
      "Javier Bardem",
      "Mads Mikkelsen",
      "Ralph Fiennes",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Christoph Waltz",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of Bond’s boss in MI6?",
    options: ["Q", "M", "R", "Z"],
    correctAnswer: "M",
  },
  {
    question: "Who performed the theme song for No Time to Die?",
    options: ["Billie Eilish", "Adele", "Sam Smith", "Tina Turner"],
    correctAnswer: "Billie Eilish",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the island lair in Dr. No?",
    options: ["Crab Key", "Piz Gloria", "SPECTRE Island", "Skyfall"],
    correctAnswer: "Crab Key",
  },
  {
    question: "Which Bond movie introduced the character Felix Leiter?",
    options: ["Dr. No", "Goldfinger", "Thunderball", "The Spy Who Loved Me"],
    correctAnswer: "Dr. No",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which actor portrayed Bond for the first time in Casino Royale (2006)?",
    options: ["Pierce Brosnan", "Roger Moore", "Daniel Craig", "Sean Connery"],
    correctAnswer: "Daniel Craig",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the villain in The Man with the Golden Gun?",
    options: ["Le Chiffre", "Scaramanga", "Dr. No", "Goldfinger"],
    correctAnswer: "Scaramanga",
  },
  {
    question: "Which Bond film features a skiing chase in the Alps?",
    options: [
      "On Her Majesty's Secret Service",
      "Moonraker",
      "A View to a Kill",
      "For Your Eyes Only",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "On Her Majesty's Secret Service",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What card game does Bond play against Le Chiffre in Casino Royale?",
    options: ["Poker", "Blackjack", "Bridge", "Baccarat"],
    correctAnswer: "Poker",
  },
  {
    question: "Which James Bond film was released in 1977?",
    options: [
      "The Spy Who Loved Me",
      "Moonraker",
      "For Your Eyes Only",
      "Live and Let Die",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "The Spy Who Loved Me",
  },
  {
    question: "Who directed the Bond movie Skyfall?",
    options: ["Sam Mendes", "Martin Campbell", "Guy Hamilton", "John Glen"],
    correctAnswer: "Sam Mendes",
  },
  {
    question: "What was the name of the villain in Quantum of Solace?",
    options: ["Dominic Greene", "Silva", "Dr. No", "Goldfinger"],
    correctAnswer: "Dominic Greene",
  },
  {
    question: "Which Bond film features the character of Pussy Galore?",
    options: ["Goldfinger", "Dr. No", "Diamonds Are Forever", "Thunderball"],
    correctAnswer: "Goldfinger",
  },
  {
    question: "In which Bond film does Judi Dench first appear as M?",
    options: [
      "GoldenEye",
      "Tomorrow Never Dies",
      "The World Is Not Enough",
      "Casino Royale",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "GoldenEye",
  },
  {
    question: "Who plays the role of Q in the Daniel Craig Bond movies?",
    options: [
      "Ben Whishaw",
      "John Cleese",
      "Desmond Llewelyn",
      "Ralph Fiennes",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Ben Whishaw",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the title of the James Bond film where Bond goes rogue?",
    options: [
      "License to Kill",
      "Skyfall",
      "Casino Royale",
      "Quantum of Solace",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "License to Kill",
  },
  {
    question: "Who was the Bond villain in The World Is Not Enough?",
    options: ["Renard", "Silva", "Le Chiffre", "Dr. No"],
    correctAnswer: "Renard",
  },
  {
    question: "Which Bond film is set mostly in Japan?",
    options: [
      "You Only Live Twice",
      "Moonraker",
      "The Man with the Golden Gun",
      "Live and Let Die",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "You Only Live Twice",
  },
  {
    question: "Which James Bond film features the villain Max Zorin?",
    options: [
      "A View to a Kill",
      "The Living Daylights",
      "GoldenEye",
      "Octopussy",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "A View to a Kill",
  },
  {
    question: "Who directed the Bond movie Casino Royale (2006)?",
    options: ["Martin Campbell", "Sam Mendes", "Guy Hamilton", "John Glen"],
    correctAnswer: "Martin Campbell",
  },
  {
    question: "Which actor starred in the most James Bond films?",
    options: ["Roger Moore", "Sean Connery", "Daniel Craig", "Pierce Brosnan"],
    correctAnswer: "Roger Moore",
  },
  {
    question: "Which Bond film was released in 1989?",
    options: [
      "License to Kill",
      "The Living Daylights",
      "Octopussy",
      "A View to a Kill",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "License to Kill",
  },
  {
    question: "In which Bond film does Bond battle a villain named Silva?",
    options: ["Skyfall", "Casino Royale", "Quantum of Solace", "Spectre"],
    correctAnswer: "Skyfall",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the intelligence organization Bond works for?",
    options: ["CIA", "MI6", "KGB", "SPECTRE"],
    correctAnswer: "MI6",
  },
  {
    question: "Who played the character of Moneypenny in Skyfall?",
    options: ["Naomie Harris", "Eva Green", "Monica Bellucci", "Rosamund Pike"],
    correctAnswer: "Naomie Harris",
  },
  {
    question: "Which Bond film features the song 'Nobody Does It Better'?",
    options: [
      "The Spy Who Loved Me",
      "Moonraker",
      "Live and Let Die",
      "For Your Eyes Only",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "The Spy Who Loved Me",
  },
  {
    question: "Which Bond movie features a car that can turn into a submarine?",
    options: ["The Spy Who Loved Me", "Moonraker", "GoldenEye", "Thunderball"],
    correctAnswer: "The Spy Who Loved Me",
  },
  {
    question: "Which actor played Bond in Tomorrow Never Dies?",
    options: ["Pierce Brosnan", "Roger Moore", "Daniel Craig", "Sean Connery"],
    correctAnswer: "Pierce Brosnan",
  },
  {
    question: "Who played the villainous Raoul Silva in Skyfall?",
    options: [
      "Javier Bardem",
      "Christoph Waltz",
      "Mads Mikkelsen",
      "Rami Malek",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Javier Bardem",
  },
];

export default JamesBondQuestions;
